title and brief overview title hackathon
Heroes an interactive platform for
collaborative Innovation brief overview
hackathon Heroes is a comprehensive
platform designed to facilitate and
manage hackathons it encompasses a wide
range of functionalities including user
authentication posting updates
displaying news feeds creating and
joining challenges maintaining
leaderboards managing administrative
tasks and sending
notifications the platform aims to
provide a seamless experience for
participants and organizers fostering
creativity collaboration and
Innovation
objectives facilitate secure user
registration and
authentication enable users to create
edit delete and view
posts provide a dynamic Newsfeed
displaying the latest
posts allow users to create join and
participate in various
challenges maintain accurate and
realtime
leaderboards offer comprehensive admin
functionalities for user and content
management deliver real-time
notifications for user
activities of
perspective new 5p hackathon Heroes is a
new project developed from scratch
designed to offer an integrated solution
for managing hackathons it does not
extend an old FP or merge features from
different existing products but
introduces a unique Consolidated
platform technical
aspect operating system compatible with
with multiple operating systems Windows
Mac OS
Linux ID Visual Studio code SDK
Frameworks frontend
HTML CSS bootstrap JavaScript backend
PHP
laravel aim engine not
applicable database management system
dbmm ql for handling data
storage application area solving a re
life problem hacker on Heroes addresses
the need for a streamlined efficient
platform to organize and participate in
hackathons it is designed to solve real
life problems faced by organizers and
participants such as managing user
authentication tracking challenges
updating leaderboards and sending
notifications the platform supports
Innovation and collaboration making it
ideal for educational institutions Tech
communities and organizations looking to
Foster creativity and problemsolving
skills this is the registration page
where users can register themselves this
is the login page without registration
users cannot log in to the homepage
after logging in this is the homepage
and on the left side there is a posting
section where you can see the latest
posts from all users and a comment bar
under each post allowing you to comment
on the user's Post in the posting
section there is a create post button
where you can create a post on the right
side you'll also see a notification icon
when you click on it you can view the
notifications you have received on the
right side there are link buttons to
navigate to the next page named profile
leaderboard search challenge 1v1
tournament settings here is the search
page on the search page users can search
for other users or anything they are
looking for on the platform here is the
profile page it will display the user's
profile picture and further details such
as name email address bio skills and
links to additional websites or
portfolios that the user can view here
tournament page here users can create
tournaments and manage them directly on
this page multiple users can come here
to see who is organizing tournaments and
can also join them here is the
leaderboard page on this page you can
see all users points and their positions
it will be continuously updated based on
users performance with points increasing
or decreasing causing their rankings to
go up or down here is the settings page
this page provides multiple settings
that users can utilize accounts users
can manage their accounts notifications
users can enable or disable different
types of platform notifications
appearance users can customize the
platform to their preferences such as
theme and other visual elements privacy
security users can manage their account
privacy and enhance security help
support if users need help with anything
on the website they can find complete
information here about users can find
details about the platform and its
creators this structured approach
ensures that the hackathon heroes
project is well organized with separate
concerns for user authentication posting
and challenges all tied together through
database relationships models and
controllers the use of middleware
ensures that only authenticated users
can perform certain actions